Xardas: Chapter Four.
Xardas: Capitolul patru.
Reinhard: Welcome to the Gothic 1 Remake podcast. I'm Reinhard Pollice, and for the first time listeners, I'm the founder and studio director at Alkimia Interactive. And I'm waiting for our composer, Kai Rosenkranz. I'm in the Old Camp Castle, and Kai should be here any minute. While we were waiting... Let me start with saying thank you to all you many listeners out there.
Reinhard: Bine ați venit la podcastul Gothic 1 Remake. Sunt Reinhard Pollice și, pentru cei care ne ascultă pentru prima dată, sunt fondatorul și directorul de studio al Alkimia Interactive. Și îl aștept pe compozitorul nostru, Kai Rosenkranz. Sunt în castelul Taberei Vechi, iar Kai ar trebui să fie aici în orice moment. În timp ce așteptăm... Permiteți-mi să încep prin a vă spune mulțumesc tuturor ascultătorilor.
Reinhard: We enjoy taking the time out of our normal schedules to stroll around in the colony and chat about the development of the Gothic 1 Remake, and it's so much more fun knowing that you guys actually enjoy it. So thanks for following along.
Reinhard: Ne face plăcere să ne luăm timp din programul nostru normal pentru a ne plimba prin colonie și a discuta despre dezvoltarea Gothic 1 Remake, și este mult mai distractiv să știm că vouă chiar vă place. Așa că vă mulțumim că ne urmăriți.
Kai: Whew, I'm here! Sorry I'm late.
Kai: Uff, sunt aici! Scuze pentru întârziere.
Reinhard: No worries. We just started.
Reinhard: Nicio grijă. Abia am început.
Kai: Thorus wouldn't let me into the castle set. I had to convince him that I'm actually the composer for the remake.
Kai: Thorus nu m-a lăsat să intru în decorul castelului. A trebuit să îl conving că eu sunt de fapt compozitorul pentru remake.
Reinhard: Oh, my. How did you do it?
Reinhard: O, vai. Cum ai reușit să faci asta?
Kai: Let's just say I didn't need those 1.000 ore anyways. So it's good I don't have to carry them around all day.
Kai: Să spunem doar că oricum nu aveam nevoie de cele 1000 pepite de minereu. Așa că mă bucur că nu trebuie să le port cu mine toată ziua.
Reinhard: Ha! He takes his job really very seriously. Dani, come on over here. He's here.
Reinhard: Ha! Își ia slujba foarte în serios. Dani, vino încoace. A ajuns.
Dani: Hey, guys. What's up?
Dani: Hei, băieți. Care-i treaba?
Reinhard: Welcome to the podcast, Dani. (Kai: Hi.)
Reinhard: Bine ai venit la podcast, Dani. (Kai: Salut.)
Dani: Hey, Kai. Do you actually sleep in the Old Camp ring?
Dani: Hei, Kai. Tu chiar dormi în inelul Taberei Vechi?
Kai: Yes. It was a dream come true. I always wanted to do it.
Kai: Da. A fost un vis devenit realitate. Tot timpul mi-am dorit să fac asta.
Dani: But which hut where you sleeping in?
Dani: Dar în ce colibă dormi?
Kai: I know there was a hut for me near the arena, but Mud ended up being very persistent.
Kai: Știu că era o colibă pentru mine lângă arenă, dar Mud a ajuns să fie foarte insistent.
Reinhard: Okay, I won't ask then if you got any rest or if he had some more questions for you.
Reinhard: Bine, nu te voi întreba atunci dacă te-ai odihnit sau dacă mai are întrebări pentru tine.
Kai: No. Not really. No. So have you already been introduced?
Kai: Nu. Nu chiar. Nu. Deci, ai fost deja prezentat?
Dani: Me? Not yet.
Dani: Eu? Nu încă.
Reinhard: Right! So this is Daniel Candil, our art director. Thanks for joining us in this episode.
Reinhard: Bine! Deci, acesta este Daniel Candil, directorul nostru artistic. Mulțumim că ni te-ai alăturat în episodul de față.
Dani: It's my pleasure.
Dani: Plăcerea e de partea mea.
Reinhard: So let's climb up to the tower. What better place to talk about the visual side of the game than up there, where we can have a great view over the whole world?
Reinhard: Așadar, să urcăm în turn. Ce loc mai bun pentru a vorbi despre partea vizuală a jocului decât acolo sus, unde putem avea o priveliște minunată asupra întregii lumi?
Dani: Oh, yeah. That sounds great.
Dani: O, da. Sună grozav.
Kai: What does an art director do exactly?
Kai: Ce face mai exact un director artistic?
Dani: Well. Good question. In general, we could say that the art director in a video game is the driving force behind the game's aesthetics. But more than that, the job for an art director is about crafting and creating coherence in the game's aesthetic vision. In our case, I would say that I work within an incredible team of artists and I am just a responsible for defining and overseeing the visual direction of the game, or ensuring all visual aspects from characters and settings to environments, the color, or even the light, or even the user interface.
Dani: Ei bine. Bună întrebare. În general, am putea spune că directorul artistic al unui joc video este motorul din spatele esteticii jocului. Dar mai mult decât atât, munca unui director artistic constă în a crea coerență în viziunea estetică a jocului. În cazul nostru, aș spune că lucrez cu o echipă incredibilă de artiști și sunt responsabil doar pentru definirea și supervizarea direcției vizuale a jocului, sau pentru garantarea tuturor aspectelor vizuale, de la personaje și decoruri la medii, culori, sau chiar lumina și interfața de utilizator.
Dani: Everything is aligning within unified vision. (Kai: M-hm.) And maybe you could think, okay then, so you spend your day modeling and doing cool 3D or 2D art. And yes... and no. Because the art director is also tasked with guiding and supervising the team of artists. And this can include reviewing our work, providing feedback, ensuring the game's vision remains consistent. And the most important part...
Dani: Totul se aliniază în cadrul unei viziuni unitare. (Kai: Îhî.) Și poate v-ați putea gândi, bine atunci, deci îți petreci ziua modelând și făcând artă 3D sau 2D. Și da... și nu. Pentru că directorul artistic are, de asemenea, sarcina de a ghida și supraveghea echipa de artiști. Iar acest lucru poate include analizarea muncii noastre, acordarea de feedback, asigurarea că viziunea jocului rămâne consecventă. Și cea mai importantă parte...
Dani: I need to be capable of motivating and steering the amazing team of artists with different specialties we have here at Alkimia. So, I could go hours and hours because, you know, art is my passion, but I think you get the point.
Dani: Trebuie să fiu capabil să motivez și să conduc echipa uimitoare de artiști cu diferite specializări pe care o avem aici la Alkimia. Aș putea continua ore în șir pentru că, știți, arta este pasiunea mea, dar cred că ați înțeles ideea.
Kai: Yes, absolutely. Thank you.
Kai: Da, absolut. Mulțumesc.
Reinhard: So, this episode might be a bit challenging since we'll have to talk about visual aspects in a podcast. How do we go about this?
Reinhard: Deci, acest episod ar putea fi un pic provocator, deoarece va trebui să vorbim despre aspectele vizuale într-un podcast. Cum abordăm acest subiect?
Dani: Well, some visual material is already out there. So we can talk about that and people can look at it while we do.
Dani: Ei bine, unele materiale vizuale există deja. Așa că putem vorbi despre asta, iar oamenii se pot uita la ele în timp ce noi vorbim.
Kai: Yeah. Great idea. For example, the Old Mine was shown in the Old Mine teaser quite a while ago.
Kai: Da. Excelentă idee. De exemplu, Mina Veche a fost prezentată în teaserul Minei Vechi cu ceva timp în urmă.
Reinhard: We showed off the Old Camp in a trailer too.
Reinhard: Am arătat și Tabăra Veche într-un trailer.
Dani: Yeah, that's a good starting point.
Dani: Da, acesta e un bun punct de plecare.
Kai: So, we are in the Old Camp - in the castle, to be precise - so why not use this to explain the creation process of, for example, the characters and the armors and your role in it?
Kai: Așadar, ne aflăm în Tabăra Veche - în castel, mai exact - așa că de ce să nu ne folosim de acest lucru pentru a explica procesul de creare, de exemplu, a personajelor și armurilor și rolul tău în acest proces?
Dani: So, well, everything starts with a complete analysis of what was previously done. Remember that we are doing a very faithful remake. So first we need to understand the decisions made back in the day and if those can work in today's world. So we are trying to modernize what should be modernized, but maintaining the essence of what should be maintained.
Dani: Ei bine, totul începe cu o analiză completă a ceea ce a fost făcut anterior. Amintiți-vă că facem un remake foarte fidel. Deci, mai întâi trebuie să înțelegem deciziile luate în trecut și dacă acestea pot funcționa în lumea de astăzi. Așadar, încercăm să modernizăm ceea ce trebuie modernizat, dar menținând esența a ceea ce trebuie menținut.
Dani: I mean, the idea is you will see a shadow and you will recognize it as a shadow. And when we finish that process, an artist starts creating concepts, gathering information, and once the design is approved, we go to the high model phase. Then we bake everything into an in-game model, we texture it. Remember: We are aiming always for very high detail armors.
Dani: Adică, ideea este că veți vedea o umbră și o veți recunoaște ca fiind o umbră. Și când terminăm acest proces, un artist începe să creeze concepte, să adune informații, iar odată ce designul este aprobat, trecem la faza de modelare înaltă. Apoi coacem totul într-un model în joc, îl texturizăm. Nu uitați: ne propunem întotdeauna armuri foarte detaliate.
Dani: And once the process is done, we integrate the pieces into the engine where we finish polishing and tweaking the final look.
Dani: După ce procesul este finalizat, integrăm piesele în motorul jocului, unde finalizăm șlefuirea și ajustarea aspectului final.
Kai: And very successfully indeed. It looks fantastic in the game.
Kai: Și, într-adevăr, cu un rezultat deosebit. Arată fantastic în joc.
Reinhard: There we are at the top of the old camp tower.
Reinhard: Iată-ne în vârful turnului Taberei Vechi.
Kai: Oh, wow, look at that. What a view.
Kai: O, uau, priviți la asta. Ce priveliște.
Dani: Yeah, it's pretty neat. Just ignore the missing pieces of landscape over there, right?
Dani: Da, e destul de frumos. Numai să ignori bucățile lipsă de peisaj de acolo, da?
Kai: (laughs) Sure.
Kai: (râde) Cu siguranță.
Reinhard: Ehm, how many people are actually working in the art department here at Alkimia? And what sort of roles do we have in here?
Reinhard: Ăăă, câți oameni lucrează efectiv în departamentul de artă aici, la Alkimia? Și ce fel de roluri avem aici?
Dani: Yeah, we are a lot of people, man. I mean, more than 30 working as I would define as the in-house team. But at the same time, we are working with different external outsourcing studios. So the number of artists involved in this is pretty high. And about roles here: We have from 2D artist to 3D artist, people who are more into character creation, people into environment, art, tech artists, lighting artists, effects artists, animators, riggers, cinematic artists.
Dani: Da, suntem o grămadă de oameni. Adică, mai mult de 30 de persoane care lucrează în ceea ce eu aș descrie ca fiind echipa internă. Dar, în același timp, lucrăm cu diferite studiouri externe de outsourcing. Așa că numărul de artiști implicați în proiect este destul de mare. Iar despre roluri: Avem de la artiști 2D la artiști 3D, oameni care se ocupă mai mult de crearea personajelor, oameni care se ocupă de mediu, artă, artiști tehnici, artiști de lumini, artiști de efecte, animatori, riggeri, artiști cinematici.
Dani: And the last time, believe me, the ones who save my life day after day: We have two amazing art coordinators.
Dani: Și pentru ultima dată, credeți-mă, cei care îmi salvează viața zi de zi: avem doi coordonatori artistici extraordinari.
Kai: Yeah, I can imagine getting some of that coordination hassle off of your own personal desk is really helpful. (Dani: Yes.) By the way, from up here you can pretty much see all of the magic barrier.
Kai: Da, îmi imaginez că este foarte de ajutor să scapi de o parte din bătaia de cap cu coordonarea de pe biroul tău personal. (Dani: Da.) Apropo, de aici de sus poți vedea cam toată bariera magică.
Dani: Oh, the barrier, man. It's always there. Like... alive, like... breathing. (Kai: Yeah.) Remembering us we are trapped!
Dani: O, bariera, omule. E mereu acolo. Parcă... vie, parcă... respiră. (Kai: Da.) Ne amintește că suntem captivi!
Kai: Yeah, that that as well.
Kai: Da, și asta.
Reinhard: So, Dani, which specific piece of art for the Gothic 1 Remake are you most proud of - for now?
Reinhard: Deci, Dani, de care dintre creațiile artistice făcute special pentru Gothic 1 Remake ești cel mai mândru, până acum?
Dani: Well, all of the pieces done have a special place in my heart, you know? But I cannot wait to see people walking through the New Camp. The rice fields... I love it! I love that place. And I have a very good feeling about Xardas' tower. You will see.
Dani: Ei bine, toate creațiile finalizate au un loc special în inima mea, știi? Dar abia aștept să văd oamenii mergând prin Tabăra Nouă. Câmpurile de orez... Le ador! Ador locul acela. Și am un sentiment foarte bun legat de turnul lui Xardas. Veți vedea.
Kai: Yeah, I think I know what you mean. I've been in both of Xardas' towers just recently to place some sound effects and... yeah! Yeah yeah yeah yeah. And which part of the asset creation turned out to be the most challenging so far?
Kai: Da, cred că știu ce vrei să spui. Am fost recent în ambele turnuri ale lui Xardas pentru a adăuga niște efecte sonore și... da! Da, da, da, da. Și care parte a creării materialelor s-a dovedit a fi cea mai dificilă până acum?
Dani: The characters, no doubt. We are trying to push our boundaries here. And we will have thousands of characters and we are trying to make each one of them unique. So imagine the work behind this. The good thing is that we have our sister company, Gate 21, helping us with that fight. So I'm convinced together will rise to victory. (Kai: Yeah.)
Dani: Personajele, fără îndoială. Încercăm să ne depășim limitele aici. Vom avea mii de personaje și încercăm să le facem pe fiecare dintre ele unice. Așa că imaginați-vă munca din spatele acestui lucru. Lucrul bun este că avem compania noastră soră, Gate 21, care ne ajută în această luptă. Așa că sunt convins că împreună vom învinge. (Kai: Da.)
Reinhard: Thanks. Very interesting. As you all know, the first thing people saw from the remake was the playable teaser. After that, we started from scratch and transitioned over to a new, more dark visual esthetics.
Reinhard: Mulțumesc. Foarte interesant. După cum știți cu toții, primul lucru pe care oamenii l-au văzut din remake a fost teaserul jucabil. După aceea, am început de la zero și am trecut la o nouă estetică vizuală, mai întunecată.
Dani: Yeah, completely.
Dani: Da, în totalitate.
Reinhard: What was the process like and how would you describe the new style?
Reinhard: Cum a fost procesul și cum ai descrie noul stil?
Dani: Yeah, on the PT - well, the Playable Teaser - we were trying to move things into a different direction. I think it has been said, but we wanted to discover the limits and see what people wanted and how far we should go. Was there a remake or was a complete reimagination of the story more in line with a modern and colorful and cheery approach?
Dani: Da, în PT - ei bine, Playable Teaser - am încercat să mutăm lucrurile într-o direcție diferită. Cred că s-a mai spus, dar am vrut să descoperim limitele și să vedem ce vor oamenii și cât de departe ar trebui să mergem. A fost vorba de un remake sau de o reimaginare completă a poveștii, mai în ton cu o abordare modernă, colorată și veselă?
Dani: Or maybe we should go deeper into the darkness, gritty, believable and moody atmosphere of the original has, respecting what made Gothic so special? Well, now the answer should be clear because we asked the community and they showed us the right path. So this time we're going for something darker. Definitely more grounded, realistic, even gritty. I wouldn't say depressive, but definitely not lush or cheer as the PT was.
Dani: Sau poate ar trebui să mergem mai în profunzime în atmosfera întunecată, curajoasă, credibilă și mohorâtă a originalului, respectând ceea ce a făcut Gothic atât de special? Ei bine, acum răspunsul ar trebui să fie clar pentru că am întrebat comunitatea și ne-au arătat calea cea bună. Așa că, de data aceasta, ne îndreptăm spre ceva mai întunecat. Cu siguranță mai bine ancorat, mai realist, chiar mai dur. Nu aș spune depresiv, dar cu siguranță nu luxuriant sau vesel cum a fost PT.
Dani: We want to enhance the original feeling and and as you saw in the trailers, we are following that path, but we have still work to do until we nail the perfect atmosphere. Listening to the fans is an important part here and believe me, we do!
Dani: Vrem să îmbunătățim sentimentul original și, după cum ați văzut în trailere, urmăm această cale, dar mai avem de lucru până când vom crea atmosfera perfectă. Să îi asculți pe fani e un lucru important aici și credeți-mă, o facem!
Kai: Oh yeah.
Kai: O, da.
Dani: In terms of style, I would say we are pursuing a "heightened realism", something that feels believable with a very high detail frequency, but that not means necessarily it's real. It just feels like it is.
Dani: În ceea ce privește stilul, aș spune că urmărim un „realism accentuat”, ceva care pare credibil cu o frecvență foarte ridicată a detaliilor, dar asta nu înseamnă neapărat că este real. Doar se simte că este.
Kai: Heightened Realism! Okay, gotta put that in my vocabulary book. Do you have like an art Bible?
Kai: Realism accentuat! Bine, trebuie să adaug asta în vocabularul meu. Aveți un fel de Biblie a artei?
Dani: Of course we have it.
Dani: Bineînțeles că o avem.
Kai: Okay. What's that? And what's covered by it?
Kai: Bine. Ce este asta? Și ce cuprinde?
Dani: Sure. I mean, we have in an art bible. And in that bible we cover the use of color, the main shapes for elements, the way we decorate, the visual strategies we use to create environments, the types of materials... It's a very complex document. And the good part is that it's an evolving document that grows naturally with the game.
Dani: Sigur. Adică, avem o biblie a artei. Și în acea biblie acoperim utilizarea culorilor, formele principale pentru elemente, modul în care decorăm, strategiile vizuale pe care le folosim pentru a crea medii, tipurile de materiale... E un document foarte complex. Iar partea bună este că e un document care evoluează și care crește în mod natural odată cu jocul.
Kai: That's super interesting! Can you give us an example of something that's in the art bible, and how you translate it into the actual game?
Kai: Asta e foarte interesant! Poți să ne dai un exemplu de ceva care se află în biblia artei și felul în care transpuneți asta în joc?
Dani: Sure. For example, in the art bible we define different strategies of color use or even decoration placement in a way that the viewer can feel the environment are bigger than they really are. And, of course, this is not something we invented. It's something that has been used in theme parks since John Hench defined "The Art of the Show" in the 60s.
Dani: Sigur. De exemplu, în biblia artei definim diferite strategii de utilizare a culorilor sau chiar de plasare a decorațiunilor astfel încât privitorul să simtă că mediul este mai mare decât este în realitate. Și, desigur, nu e un lucru inventat de noi. Este ceva care a fost folosit în parcurile tematice încă de când John Hench a definit „The Art of the Show” în anii '60.
Dani: So it's a tested thing, and it works in a real scenario. You can go to Disneyland and see it, and we use this and it just works.
Dani: Deci este un lucru testat și funcționează într-un scenariu real. Puteți merge la Disneyland și să vedeți, iar noi aplicăm acest lucru și pur și simplu funcționează.
Kai: Interesting. Thank you for that example.
Kai: Interesant. Mulțumesc pentru exemplu.
Dani: By the way, what comes to your mind when you look around? I mean, anything about this world that you find interesting?
Dani: Apropo, la ce te gândești când te uiți în jur? Adică, e vreun aspect al acestei lumi care ți se pare interesant?
Kai: Mmm... It looks beautiful. (Dani: Thanks, man. What else?) It's very diverse and - kind of - varied.
Kai: Mmm... Arată frumos. (Dani: Mulțumesc, omule. Ce altceva?) Este foarte divers și - oarecum - variat.
Dani: Yes, exactly. You can clearly recognize the different biomes.
Dani: Da, exact. Se pot recunoaște clar diversele biomuri.
Reinhard: Yeah, absolutely.
Reinhard: Da, absolut.
Dani: Oh... the biomes. So beautiful and at the same time, so challenging.
Dani: O... biomurile. Atât de frumoase și, în același timp, atât de provocatoare.
Kai: Are they still the same biomes as in the OG? Like different tones of brown-gray, but in different types of landscapes? Or have you changed the overall - like - look and vibe of these biomes?
Kai: Sunt încă aceleași biomuri ca în jocul original? Adică diferite tonuri de maro-cenușiu, dar în diferite tipuri de peisaje? Sau ați schimbat aspectul și atmosfera generală a acestor biomuri?
Dani: The biomes will be the same as in the original. And, of course, we wanted to elevate those differences between them so the player feels - like - transported. Like really immersed into another part of the world, but always maintaining coherence between them. Because in the end, the Valley of the Mines is, well, relatively small.
Dani: Biomurile vor fi la fel ca în original. Și, desigur, am vrut să evidențiem aceste diferențe între ele, astfel încât jucătorul să se simtă - cum ar veni - transportat. Ca și cum ar fi cu adevărat cufundat într-o altă parte a lumii, dar menținând întotdeauna coerența dintre ele. Pentru că, în cele din urmă, Valea Minelor este, ei bine, relativ mică.
Dani: But, you know, it's all inside the magic barrier. So, is this magic affecting somehow the biomes? We'll see.
Dani: Dar, știi tu, totul se află în interiorul barierei magice. Deci, afectează această magie cumva biomurile? Vom vedea.
Kai: Oh, look, it starts raining. So the weather system is already in place.
Kai: O, uite, începe să plouă. Deci sistemul meteorologic este deja în funcțiune.
Dani: Of course it is in place! This wouldn't be Gothic without it suddenly starting to rain and ... Hey, you can see diggers going to their huts and looking for a safe spot. The weather system is in place and I expect improvements in the next months.
Dani: Bineînțeles că este în funcțiune! Nu ar fi Gothic fără să înceapă brusc să plouă și ... Hei, puteți vedea săpătorii mergând spre colibele lor și căutând un loc sigur. Sistemul meteorologic este funcțional și mă aștept la îmbunătățiri în următoarele luni.
Reinhard: And the best part: In the remake, all the daily routines are reacting to the weather. Look how they take shelter and how they complain about the weather. But now to something we can't see from up here: We've all seen the Old Mine in the teaser trailer, and people appreciate the accuracy in which it was recreated. What are the things you decided to change about the Old Mine, though, and why?
Reinhard: Și partea cea mai bună: În remake, toate rutinele zilnice reacționează la vreme. Uite cum se adăpostesc și cum se plâng de vreme. Dar acum să trecem la ceva ce nu putem vedea de aici de sus: Cu toții am văzut Mina Veche în trailer, iar oamenii apreciază acuratețea cu care a fost recreată. Totuși, care sunt lucrurile pe care ați decis să le schimbați la Mina Veche și de ce?
Dani: Maybe we should go to the Old Mine while we talk about it. It rains anyway, so it will be more convenient inside.
Dani: Poate ar trebui să mergem la Mina Veche în timp ce vorbim despre asta. Oricum plouă, așa că va fi mai comod înăuntru.
Kai: But that's a long walk through the rain.
Kai: Dar asta ar însemna un drum lung prin ploaie.
Dani: Yes, but I came prepared.
Dani: Da, dar am venit pregătit.
Dani: This should help.
Dani: Asta ar trebui să ajute.
Kai: Whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa. I have never used the Teleportation rune before. I don't think we should... (Reinhard: DANI - WAIT!)
Kai: Whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa. Nu am mai folosit runa de teleportare până acum. Nu cred că ar trebui să... (Reinhard: DANI - AȘTEAPTĂ!)
Kai: What the h...
Kai: Ce d...
Reinhard: Shhht! Dani, where exactly did this rune take us to?
Reinhard: Șșșt! Dani, unde anume ne-a adus runa asta?
Dani: Well, usually to the most recent place that...
Dani: Ei bine, de obicei la cel mai recent loc care...
Kai: Dani. Speak quietly!
Kai: Dani. Vorbește încet!
Dani: Damn, this is dark.
Dani: La naiba, e întuneric.
Reinhard: This is the minecrawler queen's lair.
Reinhard: Acesta este bârlogul reginei târâtorilor de mină.
Kai: Oh, no.
Kai: O, nu.
Dani: Oh, crap. You're right. Be quiet everyone!
Dani: O, căcat. Aveți dreptate. Liniște toată lumea!
Kai: Oh crap! (Reinhard: Shhht.)
Kai: O, căcat! (Reinhard: Șșșt.)
Kai: No no no no no no no! Javi, hurry! We have an emergency. Sent the Templars to the minecrawler tunnels. Now! (Javi: Oh, okay. Will do!)
Kai: Nu nu nu nu nu nu nu! Javi, grăbește-te! Avem o urgență. Trimite templierii în tunelurile târâtorilor de mină. Acum! (Javi: O, bine. Așa voi face!)
Dani: Everybody RUN!
Dani: FUGIȚI cu toții!
Kai: Holy molerat. That was way too close.
Kai: Sfinte șobolan-cârtiță. Asta a fost mult prea aproape.
Reinhard: Definitely.
Reinhard: Categoric.
Dani: Sorry, guys. Last time I use the rune, it took me to the upper levels. That was just yesterday.
Dani: Îmi pare rău, băieți. Ultima oară când am folosit runa, m-a dus la nivelurile superioare. Asta a fost chiar ieri.
Kai: Hmmm! But why did someone from the team enter the minecrawler section last night? That part of the mine has long been completed.
Kai: Hmmm! Dar de ce a intrat cineva din echipă în secțiunea târâtorilor de mină noaptea trecută? Acea parte a minei a fost finalizată acum mult timp.
Dani: I don't know.
Dani: Nu știu.
Reinhard: Go and ask Alberto. We need answers.
Reinhard: Du-te și întreabă-l pe Alberto. Avem nevoie de răspunsuri.
Dani: Maybe Elena knows something.
Dani: Poate știe Elena ceva.
Reinhard: Yes!
Reinhard: Da!
Kai: Guys! We're in the middle of recording a podcast episode, remember?
Kai: Băieți! Suntem în mijlocul înregistrării unui episod din podcast, vă amintiți?
Reinhard: Oh, yeah.
Reinhard: O, da.
Dani: Yeah, right.
Dani: Da, așa e.
Reinhard: Very true.
Reinhard: Foarte adevărat.
Dani: One second! Here, torches for both of you guys.
Dani: O secundă! Aici, torțe pentru amândoi.
Kai: Ah, nice! Thank you. (Reinhard: That's handy, thanks.)
Kai: A, grozav! Mulțumesc. (Reinhard: E foarte utilă, mulțumesc.)
Kai: Ooh, look at those shadows moving around. Dynamic lighting at its best.
Kai: Ooo, uită-te la umbrele acelea care se mișcă. Iluminare dinamică la cel mai înalt nivel.
Dani: Yeah, that looks pretty cool, right?
Dani: Da, arată destul de mișto, nu?
Kai: Oh, yes. Can you talk a little bit about your lighting concepts and Unreal Engine's lighting features?
Kai: O, da. Poți să ne povestești puțin despre conceptele tale de iluminare și despre capabilitățile de iluminare ale Unreal Engine?
Dani: Yes. Of course. I mean, we moved to Unreal Engine 5 months ago because - knowing it was a risky move - we felt that the fans deserve something truly great. And the new technologies that came with UE5 let us show more detailed environments. And finally, we have the Holy Grail of light and rendering. We have global illumination in real time with "Lumen".
Dani: Da. Bineînțeles. Adică, am trecut la Unreal Engine acum 5 luni pentru că - știind că a fost o mișcare riscantă - am simțit că fanii merită ceva cu adevărat grozav. Iar noile tehnologii care au venit cu UE5 ne permit să arătăm medii mai detaliate. Și, în cele din urmă, avem Sfântul Graal al luminii și randării. Avem iluminare globală în timp real cu „Lumen”.
Dani: Three years ago, this could have been seen like a feverish dream, but we have it now and we are using it fully. Our approach in light I would define it as: "embrace the darkness". We are going full baroque where the darks are pretty obscure, where the night feels dangerous. Think about Caravaggio or Velasquez for the interiors, and Claude Lorrain for the exteriors, with those dark environments and the orange skies.
Dani: Acum trei ani, acest lucru ar fi putut fi văzut ca un vis febril, dar acum îl avem și îl folosim pe deplin. Abordarea noastră în lumină aș defini-o ca: „îmbrățișează întunericul”. Mergem în plin stil baroc, unde întunericul este destul de obscur, unde noaptea pare periculoasă. Gândiți-vă la Caravaggio sau Velasquez pentru interioare, și la Claude Lorrain pentru exterioare, cu acele medii întunecate și ceruri portocalii.
Dani: For the people listening here: If you go to Google images and search for those three masters of painting, you will see.
Dani: Pentru cei care ne ascultă acum: Dacă mergeți pe Google Images și căutați acești trei maeștri ai picturii, veți vedea.
Reinhard: So we are using a modular approach to level building, right? What does that mean and how did we apply that to the Old Mine?
Reinhard: Deci, folosim o abordare modulară pentru realizarea nivelului, corect? Ce înseamnă asta și cum am aplicat-o la mina veche?
Dani: Never underestimate the power of a simple wood plank. So basically, almost all we model and design is going to be used in different places - scaled, rotated. The modern graphic engine kind of asks you to be smart and be modular. So we created the Old Mine with seven different types of rock and ten different assets of wood structure.
Dani: Nu subestimați niciodată puterea unei simple scânduri de lemn. Deci, practic, aproape tot ceea ce modelăm și proiectăm va fi utilizat în locuri diferite - scalat, rotit. Motorul grafic modern îți cam cere să fii inteligent și modular. Așa că am creat Mina Veche cu șapte tipuri diferite de rocă și zece resurse diferite de structură de lemn.
Dani: So you can imagine how many memory and textures we are saving here. So give us three different wood planks and we will create a world for you.
Dani: Așa că vă puteți imagina cât de multă memorie și cât de multe texturi economisim aici. Deci, dați-ne trei scânduri de lemn diferite și vom crea o lume pentru voi.
Kai: Awesome (Reinhard: Guys, we have to go up here!)
Kai: Minunat (Reinhard: Băieți, trebuie să urcăm aici!)
Dani: Yes. Follow me.
Dani: Da. Urmați-mă.
Kai: Wait, is it safe to use the ladders?
Kai: Așteaptă, e sigur să folosim scările?
Reinhard: Kai! It's not 2001 anymore.
Reinhard: Kai! Nu mai suntem în 2001.
Kai: Hm, okay.
Kai: Hm, bine.
Kai: It works like a charm. Nice!
Kai: Funcționează de minune. Frumos!
Reinhard: I told you, our programing team - and especially Andre (Taulien) - already spent countless of hours on making sure ladder climbing won't be a disaster like in 2001.
Reinhard: Ți-am spus, echipa noastră de programare - în special Andre (Taulien) - a petrecut deja nenumărate ore pentru a se asigura că urcarea pe scări nu va fi un dezastru ca în 2001.
Kai: Okay. Back in the Old Camp, Javi mentioned a new wall climbing feature. Will players be able to use that feature somewhere here in the Old Mine?
Kai: Bine. În Tabăra Veche, Javi a menționat o nouă funcție de cățărare. Vor putea jucătorii să folosească funcția respectivă undeva aici, în Mina Veche?
Reinhard: Not so much in the Old Mine, actually, but there are mountain areas where real climbing is another form of traversal.
Reinhard: Nu atât de mult în Mina Veche, de fapt, dar există zone montane în care cățărarea propriu-zisă e o altă formă de traversare.
Kai: Now that I'm here in person, I have to say that the recreation of the Old Mine is really just perfect. Very true to the original, but enhanced in a really convincing and intriguing way.
Kai: Acum că sunt aici în persoană, trebuie să spun că reconstituirea Minei Vechi este chiar perfectă. Foarte fidelă originalului, dar îmbunătățită într-un mod foarte convingător și intrigant.
Dani: Thanks.
Dani: Mulțumesc.
Kai: Really, it's great! What was your process of designing the new Old Mine? How did you decide what to keep and what to extend?
Kai: Pe bune, e minunată! Care a fost procesul vostru de proiectare a noii Mine Vechi? Cum ați decis ce să păstrați și ce să extindeți?
Dani: Well, we always start with blockouts made by the design team. We meet all together since this is always a joint effort so we can share the same vision. They provide those blockouts and then we create a task force of artist to work on that specific environment. They gather references, they create the first layer, as we called it, the "nature layer", where we place all the natural rock formations ground and so...
Dani: Întotdeauna începem cu blockout-uri făcute de echipa de design. Ne întrunim cu toții, de vreme ce este vorba întotdeauna de un efort comun, astfel încât să putem împărtăși aceeași viziune. Ei ne oferă aceste schițe și apoi creăm un grup de lucru format din artiști care să lucreze la acel mediu specific. Aceștia adună referințe, creează primul strat, așa cum l-am numit noi, „stratul naturii”, în care plasăm toate formațiunile naturale de roci la sol și așa mai departe...
Dani: And once approved, we go to the "structures layer" where we design all the man-made constructions. (Kai: Mhm.) In recreating those spaces, it's very, very important to be constantly seeing and analyzing the original environments and detecting the landmarks. Walt Disney call those the "winnies" in his parks. But imagine those focal points that fans will remember when playing.
Dani: Și odată aprobate, trecem la „stratul de structuri” unde concepem toate construcțiile făcute de om. (Kai: Îhî.) În recrearea acestor spații, e foarte, foarte important să vedem și să analizăm constant mediile originale și să detectăm reperele. Walt Disney le numea pe acestea „winnies” în parcurile sale. Dar imaginează-ți acele puncte cheie de care fanii își vor aminti atunci când se vor juca.
Dani: I mean, maybe you don't remember exactly the position of the intricate pasarels that descend into the Old Mine, but I'm sure you remember the oven at the end... (Kai: Yeah!) ... and the Orc slave... (Kai: Yeah.) So those things should be there in our design too.
Dani: Adică, poate că nu vă amintiți exact poziția pasarelelor complexe care coboară în Mina Veche, dar sunt sigur că vă amintiți cuptorul de la sfârșit... (Kai: Da!) ... și sclavul Orc... (Kai: Da.) Deci, aceste lucruri ar trebui să fie acolo și în designul nostru.
Kai: Gotcha! And how many people were involved in building the Old Mine?
Kai: Am înțeles! Și câți oameni au fost implicați în construirea Minei Vechi?
Dani: If I remember well, we assembled a task force of six artists that were involved in the artistic side of the mine, from creation of the environment to the placing of ambient particle and sound effects.
Dani: Dacă îmi amintesc bine, am format un grup de lucru format din șase artiști care au fost implicați în partea artistică a minei, de la crearea mediului la plasarea particulelor ambientale și a efectelor sonore.
Kai: All right. Thanks for the INSIGHT. We're now approaching the OUTSIDE.
Kai: În regulă. Mulțumesc pentru informații. Ne apropiem acum de exterior.
Reinhard: Wow, Kai.
Reinhard: Uau, Kai.
Kai: (Inhales)... Aah, fresh air.
Kai: (Inhalează)... Aah, aer proaspăt.
Reinhard: Yeah. I suggest we walk back to the Old Camp.
Reinhard: Da. Propun să ne întoarcem în Tabăra Veche.
Dani: Yeah. Let's walk. I'll guide you for a bit, but then I have to take a different path. I have some things to do in the New Camp.
Dani: Da. Hai să mergem. Te voi conduce un pic, dar apoi trebuie să o iau pe o altă cale. Am niște lucruri de făcut în Tabăra Nouă.
Kai: interesting. Has the camp already been finished?
Kai: Interesant. A fost deja terminată tabăra?
Dani: Well, I cannot wait for you to see it, but answering your question: Yes! It's done. Maybe some lighting artist is there giving the final touches here and there, but I consider it done.
Dani: Ei bine, abia aștept să o vezi, dar îți răspund la întrebare: Da! Este gata. Poate că vreun artist de lumini este acolo și mai face ultimele retușuri pe ici pe colo, dar eu consider că e gata.
Reinhard: Kai, if you want, you can go with Dani.
Reinhard: Kai, dacă vrei, poți merge cu Dani.
Kai: Yes. Okay.
Kai: Da. În regulă.
Reinhard: I have to go back to the Old Camp and hand over that letter.
Reinhard: Trebuie să mă întorc la Tabăra Veche și să predau acea scrisoare.
Kai: Oh, yeah. The letter!
Kai: O, da. Scrisoarea!
Reinhard: Yes, but I can pick you up at the New Camp this afternoon.
Reinhard: Da, dar te pot lua de la Tabăra Nouă în după-amiaza asta.
Kai: Okay. Sounds good. Although I'm very curious who that letter is for. You've been making such a big secret out of it for a while now.
Kai: În regulă. Sună bine. Deși sunt foarte curios pentru cine este scrisoarea aia. Ai făcut un mare secret din asta de ceva vreme.
Reinhard: Well, yeah. It contains some significant news, but I want the person to get them first before anyone else gets them.
Reinhard: Ei bine, da. Conține câteva știri importante, dar vreau ca persoana respectivă să le primească prima, înainte să le primească altcineva.
Dani: Interesting.
Dani: Interesant.
Kai: Yes, very.
Kai: Da, foarte.
Reinhard: You know what? I'll accompany you to the New Camp and we can go meet the recipient in the old camp together afterwards.
Reinhard: Știi ce? Te voi însoți în Tabăra Nouă și, după aceea, ne putem întâlni împreună cu destinatarul în Tabăra Veche.
Kai: Yes. Perfect. Thank you. I'll text Timur. I think he's in the New Camp. He can meet us there with the community questions.
Kai: Da. Perfect. Mulțumesc. Îi voi trimite un mesaj lui Timur. Cred că e în Tabăra Nouă. Ne poate întâlni acolo pentru întrebările comunității.
Dani: All right. Thanks.
Dani: Foarte bine. Mulțumesc.
Kai: So, Dani, looking at this picturesque landscape, what's your approach to world design? How realistic do you want it to be - versus, like, stylized and artistic? I know we've talked about the design process and your art bible earlier, but this question is more about your artistic influences and inspirations.
Kai: Deci, Dani, uitându-te la acest peisaj pitoresc, care este abordarea ta față de designul lumii? Cât de realist vrei să fie - față de stilizat și artistic? Știu că am vorbit mai devreme despre procesul de creație și despre biblia voastră artistică, dar întrebarea asta este mai mult despre influențele și inspirațiile voastre artistice.
Dani: That's a good question, Kai. And it's something that me and Elena, you know, she's my right hand here in the team... we have debated it a lot. Where are the limits of realism? Are these or that asset falling into the stylized realm? It's something that you should be aware of constantly. As I said before, we are rooting for...
Dani: Asta e o întrebare bună, Kai. Și este ceva ce eu și Elena, știi, ea este mâna mea dreaptă aici în echipă... am dezbătut mult. Unde sunt limitele realismului? Resursele acestea sau acelea se încadrează în domeniul stilizat? E ceva de care trebuie să fii conștient în mod constant. După cum am mai spus, noi tindem spre...
Dani: ... what we call heightened realism. And this choice gives us the opportunity to work in a realistic way when we talk about materials, shape, color, light... but at the same time give us room to move into a slightly degree of stylization when we talk about magic, gods and all the fantasy themed related content.
Dani: ... ceea ce numim realism accentuat. Iar această alegere ne oferă posibilitatea de a lucra într-un stil realist atunci când vorbim despre materiale, formă, culoare, lumină... dar, în același timp, ne oferă spațiu pentru a trece la un grad ușor de stilizare atunci când vorbim despre magie, zei și tot conținutul legat de tematica fantasy.
Kai: M-hm. Understood.
Kai: M-hm. Înțeles.
Dani: I would say we need to be believable. (Kai: Yeah.) Always moving inside the limits of what is Gothic and what is not. But we should not go too real to that point where we ask ourselves if this or that design could really happen in the 12th century Europe parameters. And about references: I will pass two hours talking about references, man, but let's stay with the baroque painters. (Kai: Sure.)
Dani: Aș spune că trebuie să fim credibili. (Kai: Da.) Să ne mișcăm mereu în limitele a ceea ce este Gothic și a ceea ce nu este. Dar nu ar trebui să devenim prea realiști până în punctul în care să ne întrebăm dacă acest sau acel design ar putea exista cu adevărat în parametrii Europei secolului al XII-lea. Și despre referințe: Aș putea vorbi două ore despre referințe, omule, dar să rămânem la pictorii baroci. (Kai: Sigur.)
Dani: The way they understood the light, the dramatic effect, the theatrical composition, the play between bright and dark... I think Caravaggio and Velazquez are good examples of that. Their paintings feel real, but they were dramatic, staged and definitive. Not realistic, but they were believable. The same with artists like Claude Lorrain and his landscapes. I mean, better stop here because - Kai - I could be hours talking about the old masters and how much we should learn from them.
Dani: Modul în care ei înțelegeau lumina, efectul dramatic, compoziția teatrală, jocul dintre lumină și întuneric... Cred că Caravaggio și Velazquez sunt exemple bune în acest sens. Picturile lor par reale, dar erau dramatice, puse în scenă și definitive. Nu erau realiste, dar erau credibile. La fel și cu artiști precum Claude Lorrain și peisajele sale. Adică, mai bine mă opresc aici pentru că - Kai - aș putea sta ore întregi să vorbesc despre vechii maeștri și despre cât de multe ar trebui să învățăm de la ei.
Kai: Yeah. Seems so. I guess that's a topic for its very own, like, spinoff episode.
Kai: Da, așa este. Se pare că da. Cred că ăsta e un subiect pentru propriul său episod, ca un spinoff.
Dani: There, you can see the New Camp behind that corner.
Dani: Acolo, poți vedea Tabăra Nouă după colțul acela.
Kai: Yes. Can't wait to see it. But before we get there and you'll be busy with other things, I have a few questions about characters and animations.
Kai: Da. Abia aștept s-o văd. Dar înainte să ajungem acolo și să aveți alte lucruri de făcut, am câteva întrebări despre personaje și animații.
Dani: Sure. You'll have to talk to Gerard for detailed questions about animations, but I'll see what I can do.
Dani: Sigur. Va trebui să vorbești cu Gerard pentru întrebări detaliate despre animații, dar voi vedea ce pot face.
Kai: Thanks. First about characters: The original game had a bit of a cartoonish character style. Vivid colors, exaggerated face shapes, distinctive silhouettes, and so on. What's the plan for the remake? The characters I've seen are clearly distinguishable and super real. It's easy to tell which camp they're from and what they are, although everything seems to be a little toned down.
Kai: Mulțumesc. În primul rând despre personaje: Jocul original a avut un pic de stil de desene animate pentru personaje. Culori vii, forme exagerate ale feței, siluete distinctive și așa mai departe. Care este planul pentru remake? Personajele pe care le-am văzut sunt clar diferențiabile și super reale. Este ușor de spus din ce tabără provin și ce sunt, deși totul pare să fie un pic mai estompat.
Dani: Sure, you will be able to recognize the characters for sure. I mean, don't worry about that. We are respecting as much as possible the original design. So a guru will look like a guru and a shadow like a shadow. The challenge here was to recreate those memorable characters in a new way that felt totally respectful of the original, but at the same time offers a fresh version and I'm very happy with all the work the team did. You will see!
Dani: Sigur, veți putea recunoaște personajele cu siguranță. Adică, nu vă faceți griji în privința asta. Noi respectăm cât mai mult posibil designul original. Deci un guru va arăta ca un guru și o umbră ca o umbră. Provocarea aici a fost să recreăm aceste personaje memorabile într-un mod nou, care să se simtă în totalitate respectuos față de original, dar în același timp să ofere o versiune proaspătă și sunt foarte mulțumit de toată munca depusă de echipă. Veți vedea!
Kai: Hm, okay.
Kai: Hm, în regulă.
Reinhard: Dani, you've described the modular approach to building locations. Would you like to shed some light on the modular approach for characters?
Reinhard: Dani, ai descris abordarea modulară pentru construirea locațiilor. Ai dori să ne lămurești cu privire la abordarea modulară pentru personaje?
Dani: Well, that's a very complex topic because as you can imagine, dressing 600 characters is not the easiest thing in the world. (Kai: No.) But we are using "Mutable", an epic technology designed for creating modular characters, clothes and armor pieces, and it has been a hard fight. But luckily pieces finally are coming together. 600 different faces, a lot of different hairstyles, beards, and thousands of small pieces of armor and cloth.
Dani: Ei bine, ăsta e un subiect foarte complex pentru că, după cum vă puteți imagina, a îmbrăca 600 de personaje nu e cel mai ușor lucru din lume. (Kai: Nu.) Dar noi folosim „Mutable”, o tehnologie genială concepută pentru a crea personaje modulare, haine și piese de armură, și a fost o luptă grea. Dar, din fericire, lucrurile se potrivesc în cele din urmă. 600 de fețe diferite, o mulțime de coafuri diferite, bărbi și mii de piese mici de armură și pânză.
Dani: Now we see the light at the end of the tunnel, but we could say this has been a very fun ride.
Dani: Acum vedem lumina de la capătul tunelului, dar am putea spune că a fost o călătorie foarte distractivă.
Kai: And that's good to hear. The rice fields, just like I remember them. But what's that? That's new!
Kai: Și asta mă bucur să aud. Lanurile de orez, exact așa cum mi le amintesc. Dar ce e asta? Asta e nou!
Reinhard: Shhh! We don't want to talk about that now.
Reinhard: Șșșt! Nu vrem să vorbim despre asta acum.
Kai: Right! But ... wow, is that the Ricelord... (Dani: Oh, yes!) Wow. Interesting. Why did y...
Kai: Corect! Dar... uau, ăsta e Lordul Orezului... (Dani: O, da!) Uau. Interesant. De ce ai...
Reinhard: Kai! Shh! This hasn't been released for publication just yet.
Reinhard: Kai! Șșșt! Acest lucru nu a fost dat publicității încă.
Kai: Okay, okay! So quick question about the faces in particular. How do you make so many different faces and make them look so good? I know you've already touched on that in the previous episode, but maybe you can elaborate a little bit.
Kai: Bine, bine! Deci, întrebare rapidă despre fețe în special. Cum reușești să faci atât de multe fețe diferite și să le faci să arate atât de bine? Știu că ai abordat deja acest subiect în episodul anterior, dar poate poți detalia puțin.
Dani: Yeah, luckily we are not alone in this fight. I mean, we have the support of the nice folks at Gate 21. They are a sister company that specializes in creating faces. So together we have been working on those characters. They developed a very specific tool that lets us create dozens of different faces, mixing them, having details, changing manually specific traits...
Dani: Da, din fericire nu suntem singuri în această luptă. Adică, avem sprijinul oamenilor simpatici de la Gate 21. Ei sunt o companie soră care este specializată în crearea de fețe. Așa că împreună am lucrat la aceste personaje. Ei au dezvoltat un instrument foarte specific care ne permite să creăm zeci de fețe diferite, să le amestecăm, să avem detalii, să schimbăm manual trăsături specifice...
Dani: But of course, not all the models were done using this tech. More than 100 were fully manually worked on until the very last detail.
Dani: Dar, desigur, nu toate modelele au fost realizate folosind această tehnologie. Mai mult de 100 au fost lucrate manual până la ultimul detaliu.
Kai: Whoa! 100, that's crazy!
Kai: Uau! 100, asta e o nebunie!
Dani: Imagine we have two tiers of characters! The tier A and the tier B. Tier A are the most important characters. Those 100 characters are designed, rigged and created fully manually. And then we have the tier B characters. Those are done using this amazing technology that helps in the process.
Dani: Imaginați-vă că avem două niveluri de personaje! Nivelul A și nivelul B. Nivelul A sunt cele mai importante personaje. Aceste 100 de personaje sunt proiectate, aranjate și create complet manual. Și apoi avem personajele de nivel B. Acestea sunt create folosind această tehnologie uimitoare care ajută în proces.
Kai: Okay, that makes sense. Now about animations. I'll ask Gerard all the details, but you will let us know what your general process and pipeline is for making like people and creatures move. Are you handcrafting keyframe animations? Motion or performance capturing? Procedural animations? Fancy deep learning stuff?
Kai: Bine, asta are sens. Acum, despre animații. Îl voi întreba pe Gerard toate detaliile, dar ne vei spune care este procesul general și procesul vostru pentru a face ca oamenii și creaturile să se miște. Creați manual animații cu cadre cheie? Captura de mișcare? Animații procedurale? Lucruri sofisticate de deep learning?
Dani: Yeah, I'm sure Gerard can be more specific on that topic, but I can tell you we are using all of those cases you mentioned. (Kai: Aha.) Handcrafted keyframe animations? Check. Procedural? Check. Motion capture? Well, you should see the actors screaming and fighting in the recording zone. It's pretty crazy when an Amazon guy enters the studio to deliver something and is received by a guy is screaming, holding a weapon.
Dani: Da, sunt sigur că Gerard poate fi mai specific pe acest subiect, dar pot să vă spun că folosim toate cazurile pe care le-ați menționat. (Kai: Aha.) Animații realizate manual cu cadre cheie? Verificat. Procedurale? Verificat. Captură de mișcare? Ei bine, ar trebui să vezi actorii țipând și luptându-se în zona de înregistrare. E destul de nebunesc când un tip de la Amazon intră în studio pentru a livra ceva și este primit de un tip care țipă, ținând o armă.
Dani: And deep learning stuff? Also check. It's a complicated process because we have tons of creatures, characters, complicated environments and interactions, but in the end, we hope everything will turn out all right.
Dani: Și chestii de deep learning? De asemenea, verificat. E un proces complicat pentru că avem o mulțime de creaturi, personaje, medii și interacțiuni complicate, dar, în cele din urmă, sperăm că totul va ieși bine.
Kai: Ha! Caught your little Gothic 2 quote there!
Kai: Ha! Am remarcat micul tău citat din Gothic 2 acolo!
Reinhard: All right. Here we are in the New Camp cave.
Reinhard: În regulă. Iată-ne în peștera Taberei Noi.
Kai: Yes. Wonderful! Gosh, it means so much to me. Seeing all these places recreated so accurately and yet improved in such a fantastic way.
Kai: Da. Minunat! Doamne, înseamnă atât de mult pentru mine. Să văd toate aceste locuri recreate atât de exact și totuși îmbunătățite într-un mod atât de fantastic.
Dani: Thank you so much. I'm glad you like it.
Dani: Mulțumesc foarte mult. Mă bucur că îți place.
Kai: I love it!
Kai: O ador!
Dani: And apparently you've already made new music, right? I can hear it playing in the background.
Dani: Și se pare că ai făcut deja muzică nouă, nu? O aud cum cântă în fundal.
Kai: Yeah.
Kai: Da.
Reinhard: Shall we end this episode with some music?
Reinhard: Să încheiem acest episod cu puțină muzică?
Kai: Okay, let's do it. But first we have to meet Timur for some community questions, right? (Dani and Reinhard: Oh, yeah.) Oh, there he is. Hey, Timur! (Timur: Hey Kai.) So what's going on in the community?
Kai: Bine, hai s-o facem. Dar mai întâi trebuie să ne întâlnim cu Timur pentru câteva întrebări din partea comunității, nu? (Dani și Reinhard: Oh, da.) O, iată-l. Hei, Timur! (Timur: Hei Kai.) Deci, ce se întâmplă în comunitate?
Reinhard: Our community's dying to find out more about the game. I have some questions prepared.
Reinhard: Comunitatea noastră moare de nerăbdare să afle mai multe despre joc. Am pregătit câteva întrebări.
Kai: That's great. Bring it on.
Kai: Excelent. Dă-i drumul.
Reinhard: So here is a question from our moderator, Drago. Will the items that the player equips appear on the character itself? Secifically rings or amulets? Like, ... in original they were invisible.
Reinhard: Iată deci o întrebare din partea moderatorului nostru, Drago. Obiectele pe care jucătorul le echipează vor apărea pe personajul însuși? În special inelele sau amuletele? Adică, ... în original erau invizibile.
Kai: Reinhard, go for it.
Kai: Reinhard, dă-i drumul.
Reinhard: Okay, so ... The thing is, I mean rings and amulets, you usually don't really see them because there's always some piece of cloth and armor above them. So you won't necessarily see those. But for all other things that kind of are like a little bigger, you will see them on the character. (Kai: Nice!)
Reinhard: Bine, deci... Chestia este că, de obicei, inelele și amuletele nu prea se văd pentru că deasupra lor se află întotdeauna o bucată de pânză și armură. Așa că nu le veți vedea neapărat. Dar toate celelalte lucruri care sunt un pic mai mari le veți vedea pe personaj. (Kai: Frumos!)
Timur: Yeah, thank you. And one of the most popular questions in our community is: When is the gameplay footage coming?
Timur: Da, mulțumesc. Și una dintre cele mai populare întrebări în comunitatea noastră este: Când vor apărea secvențele de gameplay?
Reinhard: Oh, yeah. Gameplay. So the idea is to show it at, like, the THQ Nordic Showcase in August.
Reinhard: O, da. Gameplay. Ideea este să îl arătăm la THQ Nordic Showcase în august.
Kai: Oh, yes. Finally.
Kai: O, da. În sfârșit.
Reinhard: Oh, I'm sure they will love it. And one more question from our moderator LurkerShnig: How will the dialog system work? Will there be a smooth transition between the moment when you press an action button and when the dialog begins? (Reinhard: So...) Or will it be closer to Elex, for example?
Reinhard: O, sunt sigur că le va plăcea. Și încă o întrebare din partea moderatorului nostru LurkerShnig: Cum va funcționa sistemul de dialog? Va exista o tranziție lină între momentul în care apeși un buton de acțiune și momentul în care începe dialogul? (Reinhard: Deci...) Sau va fi mai aproape de Elex, de exemplu?
Reinhard: Going from gameplay to a dialog scene will be smooth and seamless. So we don't have any like fake scene that we set up, but we are applying some tricks. So for example, we use like very special lighting conditions and we obviously have a special rule set for the cameras so that we capture the emotions and the characters in the best possible way.
Reinhard: Trecerea de la gameplay la o scenă de dialog va fi lină și fără cusur. Așadar, nu avem nicio scenă falsă pe care să o creăm, dar aplicăm câteva trucuri. De exemplu, folosim condiții de iluminare foarte speciale și, evident, avem un set de reguli speciale pentru camere, astfel încât să surprindem emoțiile și personajele în cel mai bun mod posibil.
Timur: Thank you for the answer. By the way, we have never heard about this one: When is the gameplay footage coming?
Timur: Mulțumesc pentru răspuns. Apropo, nu am auzit nimic despre asta: Când vine secvența de gameplay?
Reinhard: Oh yeah, it's August. We're showing it in August at the THQ Nordic Showcase.
Reinhard: O, da, în august. O arătăm în august la THQ Nordic Showcase.
Timur: Oh, okay. And one more question from our active user Hombre: "How will the diary or the journal look like? Will it be closer to Gothic 1 or 2 or something closer to Gothic 3?"
Timur: O, bine. Și încă o întrebare de la utilizatorul nostru activ Hombre: „Cum va arăta jurnalul? Va fi mai aproape de Gothic 1 sau 2 sau ceva mai asemănător cu Gothic 3?”
Reinhard: I would say the diary is kind of like inspired by Gothic 1 and 2. So it's not like just a copy of what we just heard, like in Gothic three, but it's in some ways it's, the hero is really taking actual notes.
Reinhard: Aș spune că jurnalul este inspirat de Gothic 1 și 2. Deci nu este doar o copie a ceea ce tocmai am auzit, ca în Gothic 3, ci, într-un fel, eroul chiar ia notițe.
Kai: Interesting.
Kai: Interesant.
Timur: Yeah, great! Oh, and before I forget... When is the gameplay footage dropping?
Timur: Da, minunat! O, și înainte să uit... Când apare materialul cu gameplay?
Reinhard: Right, gameplay footage! So we are showing our gameplay footage for the very first time to the public in August this year at the THQ Nordic Showcase. Tune in!
Reinhard: Exact, materialul cu gameplay! Deci, în luna august a acestui an, în cadrul THQ Nordic Showcase, vom prezenta pentru prima dată publicului secvențe de gameplay. Fiți pe fază!
Kai: So I guess we'll see you all there then in the livestream. Timur, thanks a lot for bringing those questions.
Kai: Așadar, cred că ne vom vedea cu toții acolo la transmisia live. Timur, mulțumesc mult pentru că ne-ai transmis întrebările.
Timur: Yeah. Thank you.
Timur: Da. Mulțumesc.
Kai: Dani, thank you so much for your time. That was great.
Kai: Dani, îți mulțumim foarte mult pentru timpul acordat. A fost minunat.
Dani: Thank you. And likewise.
Dani: Mulțumesc. De asemenea.
Reinhard: Okay, turn up the music. I'll show you around. Thanks. See you all in the next episode.
Reinhard: Bine, dă drumul la muzică. Îți voi arăta împrejurimile. Mulțumesc. Ne vedem cu toții în episodul următor.
All: Bye bye, everyone. Take care.
Toți: La revedere tuturor. Aveți grijă de voi.